Take the journey of a lifetime.
Life of Pi is a adventure, drama film directed by Ang Lee.
The story of an Indian boy named Pi, a zookeeper's son who finds himself in the company of a hyena,
zebra, orangutan, and a Bengal tiger after a shipwreck sets them adrift in the Pacific Ocean.
Pi Patel, played by Suraj Sharma.
Adult Pi Patel, played by Irrfan Khan.
Pi Patel (11-12 Years), played by Ayush Tandon.
Pi Patel (5 Years), played by Gautam Belur.
Santosh Patel, played by Adil Hussain.
Gita Patel, played by Tabu.
Life of Pi is a 2012 adventure-drama film directed and
produced by Ang Lee and written by David Magee.
Based on Yann Martel's 2001 novel, it stars Suraj Sharma in his film debut, Irrfan
Khan, Tabu, Rafe Spall, Gérard Depardieu and Adil Hussain in lead roles.
The storyline revolves around Pi Patel, a 16-year old Indian boy, and a Bengal tiger named
Richard Parker, who are both stranded on a lifeboat for 227 days after a shipwreck.
The film began development shortly after the release
of the book and would see directors M.
Night Shyamalan, Alfonso Cuarón and Jean-Pierre Jeunet
involved at various stages before the hiring of Lee.
Filming was split between India, Taiwan and Montreal in 2011, with Rhythm
& Hues Studios (R&H) handling the visual effects work.
The film had its worldwide premiere as the opening film of the 50th New York Film Festival at both
the Walter Reade Theater and Alice Tully Hall in New York City on September 28, 2012.
It was theatrically released in the United States
on November 21 by 20th Century Fox.
Life of Pi became a commercial success, having grossed over $609
million, and received generally positive reviews from critics.
It was nominated for three Golden Globe Awards, including Best Picture – Drama and
Best Director, and won for Golden Globe Award for Best Original Score.
At the 85th Academy Awards, it had 11 nominations, including Best Picture and Best
Adapted Screenplay, and won four, including Best Director for Ang Lee.
The film explores themes of sea, faith, loss of loved one, 1970s, zebra.
The tone is emotional.